<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | USC QCB Liang&#39;s Lab</title>
    <link>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2015-2022 Liang Chen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/media/icon_hu6989a23ee951c653d708b725e94b0b78_382583_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our lab member Bo Sun is going to defense on March 1, 2022</title>
      <link>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/bo_sun_graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/bo_sun_graduate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good luck for Bo&amp;rsquo;s defense and dissertation. And congratulations to Bo Sun for starting a position as Research Scientist at Meta Platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bo Sun is a Ph.D candidate at the quantitative and computational biology department from Uni- versity of Southern California. In 2021, he re- ceived M.S. degree in data science from Univer- sity of Southern California. In 2016 he received B.Eng. degree from Tongji University, China. He joined Meta Platform, Inc. as a Research Scientist in 2021. He primarily researches hu- man genome and gene expressions, machine perception for image and videos, and few-shot learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper authored by our lab member Wei Jiang accepted at Cells.</title>
      <link>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/wei_jiang_paper_accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liangchen-usc.github.io/post/wei_jiang_paper_accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Wei Jiang for paper &amp;quot; Global Reprogramming of Apoptosis-Related Genes during Brain Development.&amp;quot; accepted at Cells!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable long-term survival, mammalian adult neurons exhibit unique apoptosis competence. Questions remain as to whether and how neurons globally reprogram the expression of apoptotic genes during development. We systematically examined the in vivo expression of 1923 apoptosis-related genes and associated histone modifications at eight developmental ages of mouse brains. Most apoptotic genes displayed consistent temporal patterns across the forebrain, midbrain, and hindbrain, suggesting ubiquitous robust developmental reprogramming. Although both anti- and pro-apoptotic genes can be up- or downregulated, half the regulatory events in the classical apoptosis pathway are downregulation of pro-apoptotic genes. Reduced expression in initiator caspases, apoptosome, and pro-apoptotic Bcl-2 family members restrains effector caspase activation and attenuates neuronal apoptosis. The developmental downregulation of apoptotic genes is attributed to decreasing histone-3-lysine-4-trimethylation (H3K4me3) signals at promoters, where histone-3-lysine-27-trimethylation (H3K27me3) rarely changes. By contrast, repressive H3K27me3 marks are lost in the upregulated gene groups, for which developmental H3K4me3 changes are not predictive. Hence, developing brains remove epigenetic H3K4me3 and H3K27me3 marks on different apoptotic gene groups, contributing to their downregulation and upregulation, respectively. As such, neurons drastically alter global apoptotic gene expression during development to transform apoptosis controls. Research into neuronal cell death should consider maturation stages as a biological variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/2073-4409/10/11/2901/htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;View-full text&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
